Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939. Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot: an inventory
Harvard University Archives
- Correspondence and other papers, ca. 1886-1939, HUG 4255
  - General File
    - The Study and Treatment of Heart Disease at M.G.H. from 1821 to 1936. Ether Day Address by Paul D. White, Oct. 16, 1937. (Containing a tribute to R.C.C.). (Folder Folder 152. Box 118)
    - Harvard Ethics. Clippings from Crimson, 1935. (Folder Folder 153. Box 118)
    - Philosophy. (Notes by R.C.C., April, 1937). (Folder Folder 154. Box 118)
    - Indian Magic again puzzles Scientists. Kuda Bux's Fire Walking. Photostatic copy of article in N.Y. Times, Oct. 20, 1935. (Folder Folder 155. Box 118)
    - R. C. Cabot, medical reports (Folder Folder 157. Box 119)
      - 1.) B.H. Ragle, Sept. 22, 1937.
      - 2.) G.W. Holmes, Oct. 1, 1937.
      - 3.) P.D. White, July 1938.
    - How to think. R.C.C.'s original notes, 1917. (Corrected copy with Creation material). (Folder Folder 158. Box 119)
    - Robins, Col. Raymond, medical records, letters, etc. (Folder Folder 159. Box 119)
    - Declarations of War. Pamphlet relating to Great War. (Folder Folder 160. Box 119)
    - Group Medicine, 1938. (Folder Folder 161. Box 119)
    - Correspondence: S.J. Elder and A.G. O'Gorman re. ELC Foundation. (Folder Folder 162. Box 119)
    - Northeast Church. (Box Folder 164. Box 119)
    - Origin of Hospitals. History Ref. Council. (H.C. Greene). (Box Folder 165. Box 119)
    - Shelley. R.C.C.'s reading notes on. (Box Folder 166. Box 119)
    - Alexander's Theory of Conscious Control. (Box Folder 167. Box 119)
    - R.C.C.'s address at Memorial Service to John Graham Brooks. (Box Folder 168. Box 119)
    - Palfrey Perkins. Sermon on Immortality, Easter, 1934. (Box Folder 169. Box 119)
    - Thornton Wilder on Death. Our Town, 1938. (Box Folder 172. Box 119)
    - The Creed. Reading Notes. R.C.C. (Box Folder 173. Box 119)
  - Notes of Speeches, 1917-1938
    - Card index (Box 121)
    - Notes
      Folder Numbers Box Numbers
      1-43
      Box 120
      44-89
      Box 122
      90-146
      Box 123
      147-206
      Box 124
- Material Arranged and Described in 1997
  - Biographical Material
    - Diary of ideas, 1888-1892, HUG 4255.30
      Indexed.
    - Water-colors and other sketches, (3 boxes); HUG 4255.35
    - Photographs and Engravings, (2 boxes); HUG 4255. 98p
      Photographs of family and friends sent by Ada McCormick Nov. 1958; photographs of Richard C. Cabot given by G. W. Allport Fall, 1964.
      )
      Contains photographs of RCC and his family and friends, and engravings of RCC, Ella L. Cabot, and William James.
    - James Elliot Cabot. I. Autobiographical sketch. II. Family reminiscences. III. Sedge birds. Boston: G.H. Ellis Co., printers, 1904, (1 volume); HUG 4255.84
    - Richard C. Cabot Memorial Seminar, January 18, 1958., (1 box); HUG 4255.90
      Given by Professor G.W. Allport, August 22, 1958.
      Contains correspondence, photographs, tape recording of the proceedings, and a typed transcript (122 pages). A verbatim record of a seminar on the life of Dr. Cabot, including reminiscences, and discussion of a possible biography. Organized by Rev. Rollin Fairbanks (with the Cabot Trust?)
    - Nelson, Kenneth Arlyn. Richard Clarke Cabot and the Development of Clinical Pastoral Education. 1970, HUG 4255.59
      Ph.D. thesis, School of Religion in the Graduate College of The University of Iowa.
    - Posters done for exhibition on R.C. Cabot at the Mass. General, 1981., (13 posters); HUG 4255 pf
    - Ada P. McCormick Biography Research Material, (20 boxes); HUG 4255.80
      Accession numbers
      7664
      7835
      11424, June 14, 1988
      Ada P. McCormick's research material for a biography, never written, of Ella Lyman Cabot and Richard Clarke Cabot.
      Organization of the McCormick Research Material
      Drafts
      Subject files
      APM's correspondence
      Documents
      Interviews.
      - Drafts
        - APM's notes on book (Box Box 1)
        - APM notes on Cabots (Box Box 1)
        - The Cabot Household [manuscript] (Box Box 1)
        - Cabot Materials - portions of ms., (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
        - Chapter I - I meet the Cabots (Box Box 1)
        - "Ella Lyman Cabot" by APM (Box Box 1)
        - "ELC and her Husband, RCC" [manuscript] (Box Box 1)
        - ELC chapter I II corrected by RCC (Box Box 1)
        - ELC compared to Proust (Box Box 1)
        - ELC's Honeymoon (Box Box 1)
        - Ella's Death (Box Box 1)
        - ELC (part of early sketch) (Box Box 1)
        - ELC misc. material (Box Box 2)
        - Ella Lyman Cabot-portions of Master's Thesis by APM (Box Box 2)
        - Ella Lyman Cabot reprinted from Radcliffe Quarterly, July 1935 (Box Box 2)
        - Ella Lyman Cabot (APM corrected article)
        - Foreword to Book (Box Box 2)
        - Fragments on ELC (Box Box 2)
      - Subject files
        - Aboard (Box Box 3)
        - APM speculates about RCC a "last love affair" (Box Box 3)
        - APM's dream on ELC Rosalind Greene (Box Box 3)
        - APM ELC discuss religion (Box Box 3)
        - APM Notes on Cabots (Box Box 3)
        - Appearance clothes, middle years ELC (Box Box 3)
        - Armistice Day, Nov. 11, 1918 RCC Fred McCormick in France (Box Box 3)
        - Mea Barton (Box Box 3)
        - Dorothy Best (who lived with Cabots from age 12-14) her views and comments (Box Box 3)
        - Birth Control Counsel -ELC (Box Box 3)
        - Books by RCC (Box Box 3)
        - Boston (article in FortuneFeb. 1933) (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot, Articles clippings by about RCC ELC (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot Biography (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot Biography, misc. research materials dup., (2 binders) (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot Biography, File cards (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot family connections by Louise Wolfe (formerly Mrs. Hugh Cabot) (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot Material, misc. (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot Material (termite eaten copy) (Box Box 3)
        - Cabot Material, misc. notes, portions of articles, etc. (Box Box 4)
        - Edward Clark Cabot, editor. "El Crespusculo de la libertad" Taos, N.M. (Box Box 4)
        - Edward Twisleton Cabot letter book (Box Box 4)
        - Eliot Cabot (Box Box 4)
        - "Elizabeth Dwight Cabot's letters" reviewed by Phillipa Weld (Box Box 4)
        - Faith Cabot (Box Box 4)
        - Hugh Cabot (Box Box 4)
        - Hugh Cabot, medical interview with Ada 1915 after RCC interview (Box Box 4)
        - Philip Cabot Interviews (Box Box 4)
        - Richard Cabot, printed records about him and his work (Box Box 4)
        - Ted Cabot Material (Box Box 4)
        - Ted Cabot RCC dialogue (Box Box 4)
        - Character, RCC ELC, (2 folders) (Box Box 4)
        - Chronology of Events (1866-1934) ELC (Box Box 4)
        - Class notes in Child Study -Lecturer ELC (Box Box 4)
        - Constance (Box Box 4)
        - Courtship (Box Box 4)
        - Dates, Cabots (Box Box 5)
        - Day, a typical schedule ELC (Box Box 5)
        - Death last Summer ELC (Box Box 5)
        - Debut, ELC (Box Box 5)
        - Decisions (Box Box 5)
        - Ella Boston (Box Box 5)
        - ELC misc. (Box Box 5)
        - Ella RCC improved or not by being together. Questions to Alice O'Gorman, 1958 (Box Box 5)
        - Family Lyman (Box Box 5)
        - Dr. Helen Flanders Dunbar, theo. 7 M.D. on RCC (Box Box 5)
        - Friends, death of (Box Box 5)
        - Friendships (Box Box 5)
        - Friends at Saranac (Box Box 5)
        - RCC's funeral, Alice O'Gorman (Box Box 5)
        - Excerpts from a book about War Nurses (Box Box 5)
        - Gaskell Twisleton reprint from William Wentworth story by Henry James (Box Box 5)
        - Growing Edge Interests of RCC ELC (Box Box 5)
        - Gluecks, Sheldon Eleanor Touroff (Box Box 5)
        - Hero Worship (Box Box 5)
        - Hocking, Agnes (Box Box 5)
        - Hospitality (Box Box 5)
        - Humor RCC ELC (Box Box 5)
        - Instructions to a Bride by RCC (Box Box 5)
        - Lulie Kent Beth Farley, cousins of RCC (Box Box 5)
        - Leseur, Elizabeth (resembled ELC) (Box Box 5)
        - Lessons, Winters of 1887-91 ELC (Box Box 5)
        - Letter Magazine (APM ed.) (Box Box 5)
        - Limitations ELC (Box Box 5)
        - List of file folders in APM's research papers for Cabot book/List of family friends (Box Box 5)
        - Little Chapel of All Nations (Box Box 5)
        - Little Kings Chapel (Box Box 5)
        - Little Waltham (Box Box 5)
        - Lyman Books Ancestors (Box Box 5)
        - Lyman, Herbert (Box Box 5)
        - Theodore Lyman (Box Box 5)
        - Marriage (Box Box 5)
        - RCC Materials to File (Box Box 6)
        - Medical, Ella, RCC (Box Box 6)
        - Medical Life early RCC (Box Box 6)
        - RCC's Memorial Seminar January 18, 1958, (2 folders) (Box Box 6)
        - Memory (Box Box 6)
        - Methods Outlines (biography on Cabots) (Box Box 6)
        - Misc. notes, copies of letters, some photos of APM Alice O'Gorman (Box Box 6)
        - RCC mis. materials (Box Box 6)
        - Misunderstandings between Cabots (Box Box 6)
        - Money ELC (Box Box 6)
        - Motherhood (Box Box 6)
        - Music, RCC ELC (Box Box 6)
        - Nature ELC (Box Box 6)
        - Nephews Nieces (Box Box 6)
        - Nerves ELC (Box Box 6)
        - Nervous People (Box Box 7)
        - Neurosis (Box Box 7)
        - Notebook, misc. (Box Box 7)
        - Notes by APM (Box Box 7)
        - Notes of Alice O'Gorman on RCC, ELC, Cabot Friends (Box Box 7)
        - Notes on Life Services of RCC by APM (Box Box 7)
        - Alice O'Gorman Diary July 1917-March 1919 (Box Box 7)
        - RCC notes on trip to Egypt (Box Box 7)
        - Notes on RCC by? (Box Box 7)
        - Outside (Box Box 7)
        - Paradoxes (Box Box 7)
        - Philosophy, ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Poetry, ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Quotation of John Keats (strong flavor of RCC) Ida Tarbell Library (Box Box 7)
        - Religion (Box Box 7)
        - Rudeness (Box Box 7)
        - Ellery Sedgwick (Box Box 7)
        - Self Confidence, on restoring of ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Eleanor Slater Essays (Box Box 7)
        - Eleanor Slater on ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Smoking (Box Box 7)
        - Social Distinction ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Social Life (Box Box 7)
        - Spiritual Direction (Box Box 7)
        - Summing Up (Box Box 7)
        - Teaching of RCC Walter Clark's article (Box Box 7)
        - Teaching RCC (Box Box 7)
        - Teaching ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Thrift ELC (Box Box 7)
        - Truth (Box Box 7)
        - Edward Twistleton (Box Box 7)
        - Waltham House (Box Box 8)
        - Philippa Weld re: Cabots (Box Box 8)
        - The Wedding Service (Box Box 8)
        - Notebook 1894 Wedding Trip Finances (Box Box 8)
        - Wedding Presents bought abroad 1894 (Box Box 8)
        - Wedding Trip (Box Box 8)
        - War, The (Box Box 8)
        - Western Trip (Box Box 8)
        - Paul Dudley White on RCC (Box Box 8)
        - Wistful, ELC (Box Box 8)
        - Women, RCC (Box Box 8)
        - Writing, ELC (Box Box 8)
        - Year by Year Activities, 1894-1934 (Box Box 8)
        - Ella's Youth (Box Box 8)
        - RCC's Youth (Box Box 8)
      - APM's correspondence
        - RCC to APM, (no dates) (Box Box 9)
        - RCC to APM, 1912-1937, (2 folders) (Box Box 9)
        - APM to RCC, excerpts or parts of letters (probably never mailed) (Box Box 9)
        - APM to RCC 1912-1933 (very few letters in early years, probably never returned) (Box Box 9)
        - APM to RCC 1935-1939 (Box Box 9)
        - APM to RCC re: Margaret Bradley 1935 (Box Box 9)
        - APM to RCC: Ministering to the Sick (Box Box 9)
        - Correspondence RCC to APM on writing about Ella 1935 (Box Box 9)
        - APM to RCC, 1935-1936 (Box Box 10)
          Concerns quarrel on finances on book; many not sent.
        - Ada's correspondence relating to book on Cabots (Box Box 10)
        - Correspondence: APM, Gordon Allport, Alice O'Gorman, and Marian Starkey re: Cabot Biography (Box Box 10)
        - APM letter to Gordon Allport (never sent) re: Richard Cabot and his marriage (Box Box 10)
        - ELC Trust, Gordon Allport APM correspondence (Box Box 10)
        - Cabot Book, APM excerpts (Box Box 10)
        - Cabot Book re: Contract agreement with RCC (Box Box 10)
        - Cabot Book, permission (Box Box 10)
        - Cabot Book, MacMillan Co. (Box Box 10)
        - Eliot Cabot to APM (Box Box 10)
        - Faith Cabot to APM (Box Box 10)
        - APM to Faith Cabot, 1935-1958 (Box Box 10)
        - APM to President of Radcliffe, 1952 (Box Box 10)
        - Correspondence with Mary Foote (Box Box 10)
        - Francesca Greene APM correspondence (Box Box 10)
        - Rosalind Greene APM (concern over letters, etc.) (Box Box 10)
        - APM to Mass. Med. Comm. on Ethics (Box Box 10)
        - APM to FM (Box Box 10)
        - Misc. letters about RCC ELC from friends (Box Box 10)
        - APM Alice O'Gorman correspondence during quarrel with RCC (Box Box 10)
        - APM Alice O'Gorman Correspondence re: Cabots (Box Box 11)
        - Julia Pottle (Box Box 11)
        - Eugene Rosenstock Huessy (Box Box 11)
        - Margaret G. Reilly Others (Box Box 11)
          From accession 11424.
        - Edith Rhoades (Box Box 11)
        - APM to Ida Tarbell (Box Box 11)
        - APM to Philippa Weld (Box Box 11)
      - Documents
        Documents include copies of Cabot correspondence, originals of Cabot correspondence, and journals.
        - ELC's Letters to Doris Baldwin Semper (Box Box 12)
        - RCC (age 24) describes Amy Cabot (Box Box 12)
        - Charles M. Cabot (Box Box 12)
        - Cabot, Elizabeth, letters (Box Box 12)
        - Cabot, Eliz. D. (Mrs. J. Elliot) Letters to Mother, 1885-1901 RCC (Box Box 12)
        - Faith Cabot to RCC, 1918 (Box Box 12)
        - RCC to Faith Cabot, 1917-1934 (Box Box 12)
        - Letters to Fred Cabot, 1889-95 RCC (Box Box 12)
        - Interview with Dr. Hugh Cabot (Box Box 12)
        - Thank you letters to Dr. Hugh Cabot and Charles Cabot for bound copies of Elizabeth Cabot's letters, 1905 [originals] (Box Box 12)
        - Cabot-Wolfe (Hugh's children writing after his death) (Box Box 12)
        - J. Elliot Cabot to RCC (Box Box 12)
        - Chapman, Minna, Letters to RCC, 1891-95 (Box Box 12)
        - Sarah N. Cleghorn, "St. Francis" for RCC (Box Box 12)
        - Correspondence between RCC Mea Coolidge (Box Box 12)
        - Crosby, Margaret to RCC, 1892 (Box Box 12)
        - Darling, Katherine. College Days RCC, 1887-89 (Box Box 12)
        - Josephine Duvaneck (friend of Cabots) (Box Box 12)
        - ELC RCC to Bessie Evans, 1897-1923 (Box Box 12)
        - Farley, Beth (Elizabeth Dwight Farley) (Box Box 12)
        - Mary Foote (sec. to RCC, Dr. Tillerson) (Box Box 12)
        - RCC to Mary Fuller, 1909-11 (Box Box 12)
        - Letters to Foreigners (Box Box 12)
        - Rosalind Greene to Richard Cabot (Box Box 12)
        - Harvard Letters, RCC (Box Box 12)
        - Letters to Mary Haskell, RCC, 1903 (Box Box 13)
        - Re: Hillyer Brown, Cabots keeping him from joining Episcopal Church (Box Box 13)
        - RCC re: Ernest Hocking (Box Box 13)
        - Hodder, Jessie, correspondence, 1905-1928 (Box Box 13)
        - RCC to David Hunter, 1935-1938 (Box Box 13)
        - ELC Letters to Mabel and Julia Lyman, and Helene de Bouchet (Mrs. Walter Lovell) (Box Box 13)
        - Mabel Lyman to ELC (Box Box 13)
        - Germaine de Luze to RCC (Box Box 13)
        - Library Executor, Reginald Robins (Box Box 13)
        - Misc. letters from RCC (Box Box 13)
        - Sister Maria's Letters to RCC, 1923-1926 (Box Box 13)
        - Sister Maria's Letters to RCC, 1927-1934 (and APM to Sr. Maria) (Box Box 13)
        - RCC to Agnes Miano (Box Box 13)
        - Garnet Pelton to ELC (Box Box 13)
        - Paul (Pigors?) to RCC, 1924 (Box Box 13)
        - Porter, Bruce, Letters to ELC, 1907-1912 (Box Box 13)
        - Frances Ronsmaniere letters from ELC, 1902-1905 (Box Box 13)
        - Josiah Royce to RCC (Box Box 13)
        - Letters to Mary Sears by RCC (Box Box 13)
        - ELC to Eleanor Slater, 1928-1933 (Box Box 13)
        - Betty Swift on ELC (Box Box 13)
        - Letter to Violet Tack from RCC, 1908 (Box Box 13)
        - Phillippa Weld on ELC RCC (Box Box 13)
        - Correspondence RCC Mrs. Whitman, 1889-1902 (Box Box 13)
        - Diary, 1895-1902 extracts made by ELC (Box Box 14)
        - ELC Diary, 1901, Brown, Helen and Philip (Box Box 14)
        - ELC Diary, 1918, sent to RCC in France (Box Box 14)
        - ELC Diary, 1923 (Box Box 14)
        - Diary, 1931, ELC (Box Box 14)
        - ELC's Journals (Box Box 14)
        - Journal, Extracts European Journey, May-Nov. 1885 ELC (6 months with family 3 maids) (Box Box 14)
        - Journal, 1885-1892, ELC (Box Box 14)
        - Journal Thoughts, 1898-1908, ELC (Box Box 14)
        - ELC Journal, Dec. 1902-Oct. 1913 (Box Box 14)
        - ELC Journals to RCC, 1917 (Box Box 14)
        - ELC original Journal, 1924-28 (Box Box 14)
        - Journal, 1924-27-28, ELC [typescript] (Box Box 14)
        - ELC, Extracts from journals, letters, etc. (Box Box 14)
        - ELC's Father's Death, [ca.1916] (Box Box 14)
        - Names addresses of ELC's friends, 1935 (Box Box 14)
        - Not Having Children RCC ELC, 1893 (Box Box 14)
        - Friendships (Box Box 14)
        - Invitations, 1887-1894, ELC (Box Box 14)
        - ELC to Katharine Furst, 1933-34 (Box Box 14)
        - ELC "The Irrationality of Chesterton" "A Counsellor of Loyalty and Laughter" (Box Box 14)
        - Activities of ELC, 1894-1934 (Box Box 15)
        - Articles by ELC (Box Box 15)
        - RCC articles, addresses, and newsclippings (Box Box 15)
        - ELC, books read in 1886 [original list] (Box Box 15)
        - ELC RCC books (Box Box 15)
        - ELC RCC book of prayers written by them after marriage, in 1894 [original] (Box Box 15)
        - Correspondence APM ELC (Box Box 15)
        - Cabot, misc. notes, letters (Box Box 15)
        - Clinical Training of Theologs (Box Box 15)
        - RCC's description of Lymans of Ella (Important) (Box Box 15)
        - Guardianship of Children (Philip Cabot's Children, Rosalind Harry Greene) (Box Box 15)
        - RCC Journal, Europe, 1925 (Box Box 15)
        - Journal of RCC at 18, Cabot [original copy] (Box Box 15)
        - Lecture on Family by RCC Sch. for Social Work (Box Box 15)
        - Letter to a cousin of RCC that she handed me in a book (Box Box 15)
          "Me" refers to Ada McCormick.
        - Letters, 1906, Medical Trips, RCC to ELC (Box Box 15)
        - Letters to RCC re: APM's Radcliffe article on ELC (Box Box 15)
        - Letters (copies) to ELC RCC (Box Box 15)
        - Letters from friends (Box Box 15)
        - Letters, ELC to many people (Box Box 15)
        - RCC, Letter from Red Cross re: publishing book ([original] (Box Box 15)
        - RCC, Memos notes (Box Box 16)
        - RCC, Misc. material from Gordon W. Allport (Box Box 16)
        - RCC, Misc. correspondence (Box Box 16)
          From accession number 11424.
        - RCC ELC, Misc. correspondence and notes (Box Box 16)
        - Neurasthenic Appeals (original correspondence) (Box Box 16)
        - RCC notebook of Poems [original] (Box Box 16)
        - Original Correspondence and documents (RCC ELC) (Box Box 16)
        - Alice O'Gorman to ELC (Box Box 16)
        - Alice O'Gorman's letters to her family during WWI, July 1917-March 1918, (near Bordeaux, France) (Box Box 16)
        - Prayers by Cabots (Box Box 16)
        - Putman Camp, Davidson Royce, RCC to ELC, 1892 (Box Box 16)
        - Radcliffe, ELC (Box Box 16)
        - Correspondence, Cora J. Russell to RCC, 1909-1911 [original] (Box Box 16)
        - Spanish War Letters (Box Box 16)
        - Social Life, Invitation to dinner at White House (Box Box 16)
        - "Elmer Ernest Southard" by Richard Cabot (Box Box 16)
        - RCC's Last Will (Box Box 16)
        - Cabot Wills (Box Box 16)
        - Winter Reading, 1886-1895 Lists (Box Box 16)
      - Interviews
        Interviews are with RCC, family, and friends.
        - Dialogues with RCC
          - Miscellaneous (notes, excerpts, etc.) (Box Box 17)
          - Early, miscellaneous includes birth control dialogue in 1924, inclusive dates: 1914-1924
          - Cabots' Marriage (Lack of marital relations and subject of birth control, and "the lie," 1935 (Box Box 17)
          - The Lymans, etc. (also Dr. Worcester on Lymans), 1935 (Box Box 17)
          - Various subjects, Summer 1935 (Box Box 17)
          - Various subjects, Summer 1936 (Box Box 17)
          - Dialogues with RCC, 1937 (Box Box 17)
          - Notebooks of APM (Richard Hocking "nieces" re: Cabots, 1958 Seminar), 1935-36 (Box Box 17)
          - Dialogues with RCC and others, notebooks of APM, 1916-1936, (2 folders) (Box Boxes 17-18)
          - Dialogues with RCC, notebooks of APM (Box Box 18)
          - Dialogues with RCC, Ted's Death, notebooks typed copies, 1936 (Box Box 18)
            Edward T. Cabot, RCC's brother, died in 1883.
          - Religious Discussions (including APM's joining Episcopal Church in 1914) (Box Box 18)
          - Ella's last summer, 1935 (Box Box 18)
          - Philipps Brooks, Garnet Pelton, Faith Pigors, etc. (Box Box 18)
          - On Emerson (Box Box 18)
          - Methods of reading (Box Box 18)
          - On Philanthropy, 1928 (Box Box 18)
          - Medical Life, 1920 (Box Box 18)
          - On Marriage (Box Box 18)
          - On Leading Discussions (Box Box 18)
          - On Intimacy, 1917 (Box Box 18)
          - On "Beatrice" Relation (Celibacy, intimacy, marriage, APM RCC etc.) (Box Box 18)
          - Virtue (Box Box 18)
          - On War (World War I), 1917 (Box Box 18)
          - Various Subjects, Summer 1935 (Box Box 18)
            (32 pp.) Notebook, "Important"
          - "Germaine," 1936 (Box Box 18)
          - Religion, Ethics Rel. Music (Box Box 19)
          - Sins (Box Box 19)
          - Dr. Southard (Box Box 19)
          - Teaching (Box Box 19)
          - Temptations (Box Box 19)
        - Conversations with friends and family
        - APM's notes etc., 1935-36 (Box Box 19)
        - Lilice Barnes (Box Box 19)
        - Mea Coolidge Barton (Box Box 19)
        - Helen Brown (Box Box 19)
          From accession number 11424
        - Hugh Cabot, (2 folders) (Box Box 19)
        - Philip Cabot (Box Box 19)
        - Isabel Cabot (Mrs. Sydney Cabot) (Box Box 19)
        - Sydney Cabot (Box Box 19)
        - Charlotte Lyman Clarke (Box Box 19)
        - Louise Dayly (Box Box 19)
        - Frances Roumanier Dewing (Box Box 19)
        - Mrs. Frank Duvaneck (Box Box 19)
        - Rosalind Greene (Mrs. Harry Copley Greene "Portia"), 1913-69 (Box Box 19)
        - Grace Harper (Box Box 19)
        - Mrs. Charlie Higgenson (Box Box 19)
        - Mrs. Ira Rich Kent (Lulie) (Box Box 19)
        - Maulsby Kimball, 1936 (Box Box 19)
        - Joseph Lee with ELC, c. 1917 (Box Box 19)
        - Mrs. Halfdan Lee (Nina Smith) "Will" (Box Box 20)
        - Dorothy Best Lovitch (Box Box 20)
        - Mrs. Ronald Lyman (Box Box 20)
        - Mrs. Arthur Lyman (Susan) (Box Box 20)
        - John Moors Ethel Paine Moors (Box Box 20)
        - Francesca Greene Morgan (Box Box 20)
        - Katrine Coolidge Perkins (Box Box 20)
        - Faith (Cabot) Pigors Paul Pigors (Box Box 20)
        - Peggy Bruce Porter (Box Box 20)
        - Juliet W. T. Pottle (Box Box 20)
        - Ellery Sedgwick (Box Box 20)
        - Doris (Baldwin) de Sempere (Box Box 20)
        - Eleanor Slater (Box Box 20)
        - Mrs. Fisk Warren (Gretchen) (Box Box 20)
        - Dr. Elizabeth Whitney (Box Box 20)